showme.co.za 2018-07-08

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy governs the way ShowMe Online Media collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from Users (“User”) of our websites (“Sites”). This privacy policy applies to the Sites and all products and services offered by ShowMe Online Media (Pty) Ltd.

ShowMe takes your privacy seriously and we do not share any personal information collected about our customers.

#### **What we collect**

**Non-personal identification information**

Not all information requested, collected, and processed by us is “Personal Information” as it does not identify you as a specific natural person. We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Sites. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users’ means of connection to our Sites, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

We do not collect any Personal Identification Information from Users who visit our site to READ information on our products or content.

**Personal identification information**

We collect personal information about our Users in order provide our products, services, and customer support. Our products, services, and customer support are provided through many platforms including but not limited to: websites, phone apps, email, and telephone. The specific platform and product, service, or support you interact with may affect the personal data we collect.

We collect personal identification information from Users when they make a product enquiry or request a quote.  We collect this information so that our team can respond with information or sign up customers who want to place advertising and business listings on our Sites or have a website developed by us.

This information is used so that we can deliver on the contract between ourselves and our customers. This would involve invoicing and payments; business listings and website development; marketing and other projects customers may request of us.

Users must register on our Sites to enable them to add free User generated content like classifieds, free business listings, events, jobs etc. At the time of registration, they are asked if they would like to receive certain promotional material and newsletters from us that would be of interest to them.

We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personal identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities..

#### **What we do with the information we gather**

ShowMe Online Media collects and uses Users’ personal information for the following purposes:

– To improve customer service; your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.

– To personalize User experience

– We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Sites.

– To improve our Sites; we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.

– To process transactions; we may use the information Users provide about themselves when placing an order only to provide service to that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service.

– To send Users information they agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to them. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, there is an easy unsubscribe link at the bottom of each email or the User may contact us at [privacy@showme.co.za](mailto:privacy@showme.co.za).

­From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes by email or phone.

#### **Third-Party Processors**

Should the customer elect to pay on debit order, we use the services of SAGE PAY who are compliant with the **Protection of Personal Information Act  ** (POPI) which applies in South Africa and the **General Data Protection Regulation  ** (GDPR) which applies in the European Union. No credit card information is collected nor stored on our Sites.

As we offer hosting services, we need to add customer business information onto our service provider’s system in order to register domains and host traffic and e-mail addresses . We use HETZNER, who are POPI and GDPR compliant.

ShowMe uses SendinBlue and other service providers to process our mailing lists and to send emails. We ensure that they are POPI and GDPR compliant. We do not sell our mailing lists nor share them. ****

Public Authorities: Although we make every effort to preserve User privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law, such as when we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, or litigation or other legal process or action (whether or not initiated by ShowMe) to protect ShowMe’s, our Users’ or third parties’ rights, property or safety. We will transmit data to public authorities such as law enforcement or tax authorities only in the case of a legal obligation to do so based on a request for information from the respective authority.

#### **Third Party Websites**

As ShowMe develops advertising and business listings on our Sites, Users may find advertising or other content on our Sites that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to from our Site. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Sites, is subject to that website’s own terms and policies.

#### **Security of your information**

When you register on ShowMe, we prompt you to provide a unique and robust password. Your e-mail address and password combination will serve as your login credentials. To prevent unauthorized access to your account, it’s important you select an email/password combination that you have never used at any other website.  Otherwise, if you’re using the same email/password combination at ShowMe that you use elsewhere, and if that other website or service is later hacked and your login credentials stolen, it could allow these criminals to randomly try logging into other popular websites such as ShowMe to gain access to your account.  ****

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site. As per normal practice, Users on our Sites should regularly change their login passwords. The passwords should be up to 15 characters including upper and lowercase alpha and numbers and other characters like #@$% for example.

We store all the personal information you provide on our secure (password and firewall protected) servers. All electronic transactions you make to or receive from us will be encrypted using SSL technology.

Of course, data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.

You are responsible for keeping your password and User details confidential. We will not ask you for your password (except when you log in to the website).

If our website security is compromised you will be notified of the breach and how this has affected your personal information.

#### **Media**

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

#### **Contact forms**

Information submitted through the contact forms on our Sites are sent to our company email, hosted by Hetzner.

#### **Cookies**

Our Site may use “cookies” to enhance User experience. Users’ web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. Users may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies. If they do so, note that some parts of the Sites may not function properly. ** **

We use Google Analytics to analyse our Site visits to track which pages are visited on our Site, and other general statistics provided by Google Analytics to improve our content and the User experience. The Google Analytics information is anonymous.

We have the Facebook Pixel Tracking on our Site to use the Facebook functionality to create new audiences who may find our products of interest. No Personal identification information is collected by us using the Facebook Pixel. ****

Our Sites are built on the WordPress Platform and we use the WordPress logged-in cookies – these are used by WordPress to authenticate logged-in visitors, password authentication and User verification.

WordPress Multi Lingual (WPML) cookies – these are used by our WPML plugin to identify the preferred User’s language if our Site is multilingual.

WooCommerce cookies – these are used by the WooCommerce plugins on E-Commerce websites  to track visitors and their purchased items in the cart.

Articles on this Site may include embedded content, like YouTube videos, for example. Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if you visited the other website.

#### **Management of Information**

If you register on our websites, we also store the personal information you provide in your User profile. By logging in with your username and password, you can see, edit, or delete your personal information and change your password at any time (except changing your Username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

**We protect customer data with the following Site features:**

We are SSL/HTTPS compliant throughout all our Sites. This encrypts our User communications with the servers so personal identifiable information is never captured by third parties without authorization.

In case of a data breach, System Administrators will immediately go through affected Users and will attempt to reset passwords if needed after informing the User.

You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. In short, we cannot erase data that is vital to you being our customer (i.e. basic account information like an email address).

**The right to object to the processing of data for advertising purposes**

You also have the right to object at any time to the processing of your Personal Data for direct marketing, including any subscription to our newsletters. If you object, we will no longer process your Personal Data in the future. The objections must be addressed to: [privacy@showme.co.za](mailto:privacy@showme.co.za)

**To update customer billing information** , contact accounts@showme.co.za for assistance.

If you have signed up to receive marketing emails from ShowMe, you can opt-out of receiving future marketing emails by clicking on Unsubscribe on any mail we send you.

**Timeframe for Keeping Data**

We process and store your Personal Data as long as necessary for the fulfilment of our contractual or legal obligations. Thus, we store the data as long as our contractual relationship with you as our customer obliges us to do so. After termination of our contract, we will store Personal Data only to the extent and for as long as applicable law requires. All other data will be deleted immediately when you, as a customer, unsubscribe from our Products or other services. If the remaining data is no longer required for the fulfilment of legal obligations, it will be regularly deleted, unless further processing is necessary for the preservation of evidence or the prevention of legal claims from becoming time-barred.

**Business Contact or Sales Prospect Data:** If you are a business contact or sales prospect that has provided us your Personal Data, we will store your data in our database so that we can follow up on previous business conversations we’ve had with you, provide you additional information about our Products, or assist you in purchasing our Products.

**Email/Direct Mail Campaign Data:** From time to time, we may contact our customers directly by mail, email, or telephone to inform you about upgrades, new products, promotions, or special offers that you told us you were interested in receiving (including our newsletters). However, we will not contact you with any commercial communications that are unrelated to the Products that you have purchased from us unless you have given us your prior consent to receiving such information. When responding to one of these campaigns, you may have the option to provide us with personal information, which we will use for the purpose indicated.

**Survey Data:** From time to time we may conduct surveys in respect of our products and services. Participation in our surveys is optional. However, if you respond to one of our surveys, you may provide us with personal information about you. Unless you otherwise consent, we will only use this information to determine the types of Products that may be of interest to you and to operate and improve our Product offerings.

#### **Policy Amendments**

ShowMe Online Media has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. We encourage Users to frequently check the Site for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications. ** **

#### **Sale of business**

In the event of a change in control of ShowMe ownership (i.e. ShowMe is acquired by another company), or preliminary discussions to that end, your personal data may be included so the acquirer may continue to serve you.

#### **Your acceptance of these terms**

By using our Sites, you signify your acceptance of this policy and terms of service. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Sites. Your continued use of the Sites following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

#### **Contacting us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of our Sites, or your dealings with our Sites, please contact us: [privacy@showmeonlinemedia.co.za](mailto:privacy@showmeonlinemedia.co.za)
